# **Annie Po-yee Yim**

**Data Scientist / Bioinformatician** 

Address Stiftsbogen 97 81375 München Germany

**Phone** +49 (0) 17637384536

Email anniepyim@gmail.com

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/anniepyim

Personal Website / GitHub anniepyim.github.io



PhD candidate (Bioinformatics) with 3+ years experience in analysing large volumes of biological data. Motivated and independent person committed to identifying and solving problems with proven analytical and organisational skills.

### **Education**

2014 - 2018

Munich, Germany

Max Planck Institute of Biochemistry

PhD in Biology (Bioinformatics)

(anticipated graduation in August 2018)

2013 - 2014 Edinburgh, UK University of Edinburgh
MSc in Bioinformatics (with Distinction)

2009 - 2011 Chinese University of Hong Kong

Hong Kong MPhil in Medicine

# **Experience**

# 2014-10 - Current Munich, Germany

# PhD Candidate (Bioinformatics) Max Planck Institute of Biochemistry

- Analysed high volumes of sequencing data, with R packages and command line tools
- Launched and maintained a web-based analysis platform with interactive visualisations for expression data
- Designed analysis workflows for an online cancer database
- Organised a 2-day symposium for life scientists in Munich

# 2018-01 - 2018-04 Marseille, France

# **Research Intern**

#### **Developmental Biology Institute, Aix-Marseille University**

- Analysed expression and methylation data of human liver cancer and a mouse cancer model
- Performed clustering analysis to identify groups of cancer

# 2011-09 - 2013-08 Hong Kong

#### **Research Assistant**

# Faculty of Medicine, The Chinese University of Hong Kong

- Gained expertise in molecular biology and imaging techniques through experimental and animal research projects
- Performed statistical analysis on experimental and clinical research data (with publications)

# **Courses and Workshop**

#### **MOOCs (Coursera)**

- Specialization in Deep Learning (5 courses)
- · Big Data Analysis with Scala and Spark
- · Visual Analytics with Tableau

#### **Workshop (Science Craft)**

- · Data Analysis with R
- · Scientific Writing

# Programming Languages

Python

Advanced

SQL

Advanced

Javascript

Intermediate

R

Intermediate

Scala



### Skills

Exploratory Data Analysis

Advanced

Data Visualisation (d3.js, Tableau)



Machine Learning (scikit-learn, tensorflow, keras)

Intermediate

Distributed System (Hadoop, Spark)



# Languages

English

Fluent

Chinese



German

Intermediate (B1/B2)

#### **Publications**

MitoXplorer - A Visualization Approach to Investigate Mitochondrial Functions in Aneuploidy Cells with RNA-seq Data

Yim, A. P.; Koti, P.; Dürrbaum, M. et al. (Manuscript in preparation)

Hypermethylation of gene body CpG islands predicts high dosage of functional oncogenes in liver cancer.

Arechederra, M.; Daian, F.; Yim, A. P. et al. (Publication in process)

Integrative analysis and machine learning on cancer genomics data using the Cancer Systems Biology Database (CancerSysDB).

Krempel, R.; Kulkarni, P.; Yim, A. P. et al. BMC Bioinformatics. 2018; 19 (1): pp.156

Abnormal Skeletal Growth in Adolescent Idiopathic Scoliosis Is Associated with Abnormal Quantitative Expression of Melatonin Receptor, MT2.

Yim, A. P.; Yeung, H. Y.; Sun, G. et al. Int J Mol Sci. 2013; 14 (3): pp.6345-58

### Conferences

2018-01 Tokyo, Japan	16th Asia Pacific Bioinformatics Conference Poster Presentation Defective Electron Transport Chain Complex in Aneuploidy Cells - Exploring Mitochondrial Functions with RNA-seq Data Using the MitoXplorer web-platform
2017-07 Prague, Czech	16th European Conference on Computational Biology Poster Presentation Role of Mitochondria in the Occurrence of Cancer - A Visualisation Approach
2016-11 Munich, Germany	9th INTERACT Life Science Symposium Poster Presentation Visualising Expression Data of Mitochondrial Genes.

#### **Fellowships and Awards**

**Best Poster Award** at 16th Asia Pacific Bioinformatics Conference, Yokohama, Japan (2018)

**ERAMUS+ Internship Program** for Higher Education Students, Marseille, France (2018)

**PhD Program** of International Max Planck Research School for Molecular Life Sciences, Munich, Germany (2014 - 2018)

**Postgraduate Studentship** from The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong (2009 - 2011)

### **Activities**

Organising Committee of the 10th INTERACT Life Science Symposium, Munich, Germany (2018)